<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://chunde.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://chunde.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-23T04:31:02+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">iℏ∮dͩ𝛑•💕</title><subtitle>Chunde&apos;s Personal Pages. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">LacryMmaria Olor</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2025/Lacrymaria-Olor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LacryMmaria Olor"/><published>2025-01-11T04:58:15+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-11T04:58:15+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2025/Lacrymaria-Olor</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2025/Lacrymaria-Olor/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Lacrymaria olor</strong>, a species of single-celled organism known for its remarkable ability to extend and retract a long, flexible “neck,” captures food through a combination of structural and behavioral adaptations.</p> <h3 id="structural-features">Structural Features:</h3> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Elastic Cytoplasm</strong>: The “neck” of Lacrymaria olor is an extension of its cytoplasm, which can stretch up to 7 times its body length. The cytoplasm’s elasticity allows the organism to extend its neck in different directions.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Microtubules</strong>: The neck contains microtubules, which are part of the cytoskeleton. These microtubules provide structural support and are crucial for the extension and retraction of the neck. They guide the movement of the cytoplasm, ensuring that the neck can be controlled accurately.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Cilia</strong>: The organism is covered in cilia, which are tiny hair-like structures that help in movement and feeding. Cilia around the neck assist in directing food particles towards the mouth region (cytostome).</p> </li> </ol> <h3 id="behavioral-mechanisms">Behavioral Mechanisms:</h3> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Seeking Food</strong>: Lacrymaria olor moves its neck in a searching pattern, extending it in various directions to explore its environment. This movement increases the chance of encountering prey or food particles.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Prey Capture</strong>: When the neck makes contact with food, it wraps around the particle and retracts, pulling the prey toward the main body. The food is then engulfed through phagocytosis at the cytostome.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Sensory Response</strong>: The organism’s movement and extension are partially controlled by chemical signals. Lacrymaria olor can sense the presence of food through chemical cues in the water and direct its neck towards the source.</p> </li> </ol> <p>Overall, the ability of Lacrymaria olor to extend its neck and capture food is a fascinating example of how single-celled organisms can exhibit complex behaviors and structural adaptations to survive in their microscopic environments.</p> <iframe width="720" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sq6Y54mxjOg?si=173Jb7XProjuKXuZ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="Biology"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this is what included tabs in a post could look like]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Isaac Sim with ROS2</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2025/Isaac-With-ROS2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Isaac Sim with ROS2"/><published>2025-01-04T05:42:34+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-04T05:42:34+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2025/Isaac-With-ROS2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2025/Isaac-With-ROS2/"><![CDATA[<p>Here is a very helpful video that guide me through many features of Isaac Sim. Now I know how to do simliar thing with my UniTree Go2 robot dog, which is much powerful than Boston Dyamics’ version.</p> <iframe width="720" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L1rpxRm0Q1w?si=mYO4ViXjKFkOF0Kl" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Isaac"/><category term="Robotics"/><category term="Unitree"/><category term="ROS2"/><category term="Physics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Using Isaac Sim with ROS2 with Step-by-Step Guide]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Measure Quantum Phase Flip Errors</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Measure-Quantum-Flip-Error/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Measure Quantum Phase Flip Errors"/><published>2024-12-24T07:10:10+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-24T07:10:10+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Measure-Quantum-Flip-Error</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Measure-Quantum-Flip-Error/"><![CDATA[<p>In quantum computing, a sign change corresponds to a phase flip error. To measure or detect such an error, we use <strong>quantum error correction codes</strong> that are designed to handle phase flip errors (as well as other types like bit flips).</p> <h3 id="key-techniques-for-measuring-a-sign-change-phase-flip">Key Techniques for Measuring a Sign Change (Phase Flip)</h3> <ol> <li><strong>Parity Check with Ancilla Qubits</strong>: <ul> <li>Ancilla (helper) qubits are used to interact with the data qubits via carefully designed circuits.</li> <li>Parity checks are performed to detect the presence of a phase flip (without collapsing the quantum state).</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Phase Flip Error Detection Codes</strong>: <ul> <li><strong>Shor Code</strong>: Encodes a single logical qubit into nine physical qubits to detect and correct both bit flips and phase flips. For phase flips: <ul> <li>A Hadamard gate is applied to all qubits to convert phase flips into bit flips in the computational basis.</li> <li>Error syndromes are measured using ancilla qubits to detect discrepancies.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Steane Code</strong>: A more compact error-correcting code that uses 7 qubits to handle both bit and phase flip errors.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Stabilizer Formalism</strong>: <ul> <li>Stabilizer codes like the <strong>[7, 1, 3] code</strong> work by measuring operators (Pauli matrices, e.g., \(Z\) or \(X\)) that commute with the encoded state but detect phase errors.</li> <li>A phase flip introduces a detectable eigenvalue change in specific stabilizers, allowing the error to be identified.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Using Hadamard Gates</strong>: A phase flip (\(|0\rangle \to |0\rangle, |1\rangle \to -|1\rangle\)) can be converted to a bit flip (\(|0\rangle \to |1\rangle, |1\rangle \to |0\rangle\)) by applying a Hadamard gate before and after the operation: [ H Z H = X ] <ul> <li>This conversion makes phase flips detectable using similar methods as bit flips.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <h3 id="measuring-the-error">Measuring the Error</h3> <p>Once detected, the error is corrected by applying the appropriate recovery operation (e.g., a \(Z\)-gate for a phase flip). Direct measurement of the error is avoided because it could collapse the quantum state, so the process relies on ancillary systems and indirect measurement techniques.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Physics"/><category term="Quantum"/><category term="Physics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum computing study notes]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quantum Annealers</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Quantum-annealers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quantum Annealers"/><published>2024-12-11T05:52:13+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-11T05:52:13+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Quantum-annealers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Quantum-annealers/"><![CDATA[<p>Quantum annealers, such as those produced by <strong>D-Wave Systems</strong>, are often considered distinct from “universal” quantum computers because they are designed for a specific type of task: solving optimization problems using quantum annealing. While they leverage quantum effects, they differ fundamentally from gate-based, universal quantum computers (like Google’s Sycamore or IBM’s quantum processors). Here’s why quantum annealers are not typically considered “real” or <em>universal</em> quantum computers:</p> <hr/> <h3 id="1-limited-quantum-operations">1. <strong>Limited Quantum Operations</strong></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Quantum annealers</strong> are specialized machines that use quantum effects (superposition, tunneling, and entanglement) to find the ground state of a physical system.</li> <li>In contrast, <strong>universal quantum computers</strong> are programmable to perform a wide range of quantum algorithms using sequences of quantum gates.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Key Difference</strong>: Annealers cannot execute general quantum operations or algorithms like Shor’s algorithm or Grover’s algorithm because they lack gate-based logic.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="2-no-quantum-circuit-model">2. <strong>No Quantum Circuit Model</strong></h3> <ul> <li>Universal quantum computers operate using the <strong>quantum circuit model</strong>, where qubits are manipulated using a sequence of quantum gates. This allows for precise, logical control of entanglement and operations.</li> <li>Quantum annealers, however, solve problems by evolving a system into its lowest-energy state following a process known as <strong>adiabatic quantum computation</strong>. This approach lacks the programmability of gate-based models.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Key Difference</strong>: Annealers don’t implement quantum circuits, which are the foundation of “universal” quantum computing.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="3-not-fully-exploiting-quantum-speedups">3. <strong>Not Fully Exploiting Quantum Speedups</strong></h3> <ul> <li>Quantum annealers primarily solve optimization problems that can also be tackled classically using heuristics. In many cases, quantum speedups over classical algorithms remain uncertain or marginal.</li> <li>On the other hand, universal quantum computers aim to solve problems exponentially faster than classical computers, as proven for certain algorithms like Shor’s factoring algorithm.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Key Difference</strong>: The computational power of annealers is more limited, and definitive quantum advantage has yet to be demonstrated for practical use cases.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="4-lack-of-error-correction">4. <strong>Lack of Error Correction</strong></h3> <ul> <li>Universal quantum computers are designed with the eventual goal of incorporating <strong>quantum error correction</strong> to mitigate noise and decoherence, enabling reliable computations.</li> <li>Quantum annealers do not currently employ quantum error correction, making them sensitive to noise and limiting their accuracy and scalability.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Key Difference</strong>: Without error correction, annealers are less robust for large-scale, precise quantum computations.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="5-specialized-purpose">5. <strong>Specialized Purpose</strong></h3> <ul> <li>Quantum annealers are <strong>analog quantum devices</strong> tailored for optimization problems framed as <strong>Ising models</strong> or <strong>quadratic unconstrained binary optimization (QUBO)</strong> problems.</li> <li>Universal quantum computers are <strong>digital</strong> and can simulate any quantum algorithm, including optimization, simulation, cryptography, and more.</li> </ul> <p><strong>Key Difference</strong>: Annealers are problem-specific tools, while universal quantum computers are versatile and can, in principle, solve any problem efficiently.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3> <p>Quantum annealers are real quantum devices in that they harness quantum mechanics, such as superposition and tunneling, for computation. However, they are <strong>not considered universal quantum computers</strong> because they lack the flexibility, programmability, and error correction of gate-based systems. Instead, they are a specialized type of quantum computing hardware designed for a limited class of problems.</p> <hr/> <p>Quantum annealers operate based on the principles of <strong>adiabatic quantum computing</strong> and quantum mechanics, particularly leveraging quantum superposition, tunneling, and entanglement. They are designed to solve specific optimization problems by finding the global minimum (lowest energy configuration) of a given system. Below, I’ll break it down with a simple explanation and a step-by-step example.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="how-quantum-annealers-work"><strong>How Quantum Annealers Work</strong></h2> <h3 id="1-problem-representation-as-an-energy-landscape"><strong>1. Problem Representation as an Energy Landscape</strong></h3> <p>To use a quantum annealer, an optimization problem must be reformulated into a form that corresponds to a <strong>quantum energy landscape</strong>. This typically involves representing the problem using an <strong>Ising model</strong> or a <strong>QUBO (Quadratic Unconstrained Binary Optimization)</strong> formulation.</p> <ul> <li> <p><strong>Ising Model</strong>: The problem is mapped to a system of interacting <strong>spins</strong> with two states, \(+1\) (up) and \(-1\) (down). The energy of the system depends on the spins’ states and their interactions.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>QUBO Formulation</strong>: The problem is expressed as minimizing an objective function: \(E = \sum_{i} h_i q_i + \sum_{i,j} J_{ij} q_i q_j\) where:</p> <ul> <li>\(q_i \in \{0, 1\}\) are binary variables.</li> <li>\(h_i\) are weights (linear terms).</li> <li>\(J_{ij}\) are coupling strengths (quadratic terms) between variables.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="2-initial-quantum-superposition"><strong>2. Initial Quantum Superposition</strong></h3> <p>The quantum annealer begins in a <strong>superposition state</strong>, where all possible solutions (configurations of the qubits) are equally probable. Mathematically, this means each qubit starts in a state that is a combination of \(|0\rangle\) and \(|1\rangle\) states.</p> <ul> <li>This superposition allows the system to explore all possible solutions simultaneously.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="3-adiabatic-evolution"><strong>3. Adiabatic Evolution</strong></h3> <p>The system evolves <strong>slowly</strong> from an initial simple Hamiltonian (representing an easy, low-energy state) to a final Hamiltonian that encodes the optimization problem.</p> <ul> <li>The <strong>Hamiltonian</strong> describes the energy of the system. Initially, the Hamiltonian favors superposition (low-energy state).</li> <li>Gradually, the Hamiltonian changes to incorporate the problem’s constraints (interactions between qubits).</li> <li>According to the <strong>adiabatic theorem</strong>, if the evolution is slow enough, the system will remain in the <strong>lowest-energy state</strong> (ground state).</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="4-quantum-tunneling"><strong>4. Quantum Tunneling</strong></h3> <p>During this evolution, the quantum system can leverage <strong>quantum tunneling</strong> to overcome local minima in the energy landscape and reach the true global minimum.</p> <ul> <li>In classical optimization, a system might get stuck in local minima.</li> <li>Quantum tunneling allows the system to “pass through” energy barriers to potentially find better solutions.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="5-measurement-of-the-final-state"><strong>5. Measurement of the Final State</strong></h3> <p>At the end of the annealing process, the system settles into its <strong>ground state</strong> (lowest energy state), which corresponds to the optimal or near-optimal solution of the problem.</p> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>The final state of the qubits ( e.g., $$</td> <td>0\rangle\(or\) $$</td> <td>1\rangle$$ ) is measured to provide the solution.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <hr/> <h2 id="simple-example-minimizing-a-two-variable-function"><strong>Simple Example: Minimizing a Two-Variable Function</strong></h2> <p>Let’s take a simple optimization problem: \(\text{Minimize } E = q_1 + q_2 + 2q_1q_2\) where \(q_1\) and \(q_2\) are binary variables (0 or 1).</p> <h3 id="step-1-represent-the-problem"><strong>Step 1: Represent the Problem</strong></h3> <p>The goal is to minimize \(E\) by finding the combination of \(q_1\) and \(q_2\) that gives the smallest value.</p> <ul> <li>The terms \(q_1\) and \(q_2\) represent “biases” (linear terms).</li> <li>The \(2q_1q_2\) term represents the coupling (interaction) between \(q_1\) and \(q_2\).</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="step-2-initial-quantum-superposition"><strong>Step 2: Initial Quantum Superposition</strong></h3> <p>The quantum annealer initializes \(q_1\) and \(q_2\) in a superposition state, where they are both \(|0\rangle\) and \(|1\rangle\) simultaneously.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="step-3-adiabatic-evolution"><strong>Step 3: Adiabatic Evolution</strong></h3> <p>The quantum annealer starts with an initial Hamiltonian that favors superposition. As the system evolves, the Hamiltonian gradually shifts to reflect the problem’s energy function: \(H_{final} = q_1 + q_2 + 2q_1q_2\) The system explores different combinations of \(q_1\) and \(q_2\), seeking to minimize the energy \(E\).</p> <hr/> <h3 id="step-4-quantum-tunneling"><strong>Step 4: Quantum Tunneling</strong></h3> <p>If there are multiple energy “valleys” (local minima), quantum tunneling allows the system to pass through barriers to potentially find the <strong>global minimum</strong>.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="step-5-measurement"><strong>Step 5: Measurement</strong></h3> <p>At the end of the annealing process, the system settles into the configuration with the lowest energy. In this case:</p> <ul> <li>For \(q_1 = 0\) and \(q_2 = 0\), the energy \(E = 0\) (minimum).</li> <li>The quantum annealer outputs \(q_1 = 0\) and \(q_2 = 0\) as the solution.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="summary-of-the-process"><strong>Summary of the Process</strong></h2> <ol> <li><strong>Superposition</strong>: The system starts in all possible states.</li> <li><strong>Adiabatic Evolution</strong>: The system’s energy landscape is adjusted gradually to match the problem.</li> <li><strong>Quantum Tunneling</strong>: The system avoids getting stuck in local minima.</li> <li><strong>Measurement</strong>: The ground state provides the optimal solution.</li> </ol> <hr/> <h2 id="why-is-this-powerful"><strong>Why is This Powerful?</strong></h2> <p>Quantum annealers can explore a large solution space simultaneously and leverage tunneling to escape local minima, potentially solving optimization problems faster than classical approaches.</p> <p>However, their power is limited to <strong>optimization problems</strong>, and they cannot perform general-purpose quantum computations like gate-based quantum computers.</p> <p>Quantum tunneling in a <strong>quantum annealer</strong> occurs as the system evolves through its energy landscape, and the couplers play a critical role in this process. The couplers tune the interactions between qubits, effectively reshaping the energy landscape, and quantum tunneling arises as part of this <strong>adiabatic evolution</strong>. Here is a detailed explanation:</p> <hr/> <h2 id="1-basics-of-quantum-tunneling"><strong>1. Basics of Quantum Tunneling</strong></h2> <p>In classical systems, a particle trapped in a potential well (a local minimum of energy) cannot overcome a barrier unless it has enough energy. However, in quantum mechanics, due to the <strong>wave-like nature of particles</strong>, there is a nonzero probability that the particle will “tunnel” through the barrier and appear on the other side. This phenomenon is known as <strong>quantum tunneling</strong>.</p> <h3 id="in-the-context-of-a-quantum-annealer">In the context of a quantum annealer:</h3> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>The qubits represent a quantum state that can exist in a superposition of $$</td> <td>0\rangle\(and\)</td> <td>1\rangle$$ states.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>The system evolves slowly enough that tunneling between different quantum states (e.g., from one local minimum to another) can occur.</p> <p>This helps the system escape local minima and potentially reach the global minimum.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="2-role-of-couplers-in-quantum-annealing"><strong>2. Role of Couplers in Quantum Annealing</strong></h2> <p>The <strong>couplers</strong> in a quantum annealer control the interaction strengths between qubits. By tuning the couplers, the system’s energy landscape is gradually adjusted, which directly influences the probability of tunneling. Here’s how it works:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Initial Hamiltonian</strong>:<br/> At the beginning of the annealing process, the system is governed by a simple Hamiltonian (e.g., a transverse field Hamiltonian): \(H_{initial} = - \sum_i \Delta \sigma_i^x\) \(\Delta\) is the strength of the transverse field (driving quantum tunneling).</p> <table> <tbody> <tr> <td>\(\sigma_i^x\) is the Pauli-X operator, which flips qubit states between $$</td> <td>0\rangle\(and\)</td> <td>1\rangle$$.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>In this regime:</p> <p>The transverse field dominates, and the qubits exist in a <strong>superposition</strong> of \(|0 \rangle\) and \(|1\rangle\). The couplers are initially weak or inactive, so qubits interact minimally with one another.</p> </li> <li><strong>Tuning the Couplers and Reducing the Transverse Field</strong>:<br/> During the annealing process: <ul> <li>The transverse field \(\Delta\) is gradually turned off (reduced to zero), weakening the qubits’ tendency to remain in superposition.</li> <li>Simultaneously, the <strong>couplers</strong> are tuned to introduce and strengthen interactions between qubits. This gradually imposes the <strong>problem Hamiltonian</strong>: \(H_{final} = \sum_i h_i \sigma_i^z + \sum_{i &lt; j} J_{ij} \sigma_i^z \sigma_j^z\)</li> </ul> <p>\(h_i\) represents local biases (single-qubit contributions to the energy). \(J_{ij}\) represents the coupling strength between qubits \(i\) and \(j\). \(\sigma_i^z\) is the Pauli-Z operator, which measures qubits’ states as \(|0\rangle\) or \(|1\rangle\).</p> </li> <li><strong>Tunneling During Evolution</strong>:<br/> As the transverse field weakens and couplers define the problem’s energy landscape: <ul> <li>The system transitions from a state dominated by superposition to one that encodes the optimization problem.</li> <li><strong>Quantum tunneling</strong> occurs when qubits “tunnel” through energy barriers between local minima. Instead of climbing over barriers (as in classical systems), the quantum state tunnels to lower-energy configurations.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Final State</strong>:<br/> At the end of the annealing process: <ul> <li>The transverse field is turned off entirely.</li> <li>The couplers fully encode the problem’s constraints and interactions.</li> <li>The system settles into its <strong>ground state</strong> (lowest energy state), which corresponds to the optimal solution.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <hr/> <h2 id="how-tuning-the-couplers-affects-tunneling"><strong>How Tuning the Couplers Affects Tunneling</strong></h2> <p>The couplers’ role in tuning the interaction strengths \(J_{ij}\) between qubits directly shapes the energy landscape of the problem:</p> <ol> <li><strong>Weak Couplings</strong>: <ul> <li>When the couplers are weak, the energy landscape is relatively “flat,” and tunneling is widespread because the barriers between states are low.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Strong Couplings</strong>: <ul> <li>As the couplers are strengthened, the energy barriers between local minima grow, and the system begins to “lock in” on specific energy configurations.</li> <li>However, tunneling still occurs if the barriers are not too large, helping the system escape local minima and reach the global minimum.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <p>By controlling the couplers and transverse field during the annealing process, the system balances <strong>exploration</strong> (via tunneling) and <strong>exploitation</strong> (converging toward the ground state).</p> <hr/> <h2 id="visualization-a-simple-energy-landscape"><strong>Visualization: A Simple Energy Landscape</strong></h2> <p>Imagine a quantum annealer working on a problem with two qubits and two potential states:</p> <ul> <li><strong>State A</strong> (local minimum): Higher energy, but nearby.</li> <li><strong>State B</strong> (global minimum): Lower energy, but separated by an energy barrier.</li> </ul> <ol> <li>Initially, the transverse field dominates, and the system is in a superposition of both states.</li> <li>As the couplers strengthen and the transverse field reduces, the energy landscape forms a “valley” with an energy barrier between State A and State B.</li> <li><strong>Quantum tunneling</strong> allows the system to tunnel through the energy barrier and reach State B (the global minimum), even though it would be “classically” stuck in State A.</li> </ol> <hr/> <h2 id="summary"><strong>Summary</strong></h2> <ul> <li>Quantum tunneling happens as the couplers reshape the energy landscape during the annealing process.</li> <li>Initially, qubits exist in superposition, with a transverse field promoting tunneling.</li> <li>Gradual tuning of couplers strengthens qubit interactions and reshapes the landscape to reflect the problem.</li> <li>Quantum tunneling helps the system escape local minima and find the global minimum efficiently.</li> </ul> <p>By carefully managing the evolution of the couplers and transverse field, quantum annealers exploit quantum tunneling to solve complex optimization problems.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Science"/><category term="quantum"/><category term="physics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quantum annealers, such as those produced by D-Wave Systems, are often considered distinct from “universal” quantum computers because they are designed for a specific type of task: solving optimization problems using quantum annealing. While they leverage quantum effects, they differ fundamentally from gate-based, universal quantum computers (like Google’s Sycamore or IBM’s quantum processors). Here’s why quantum annealers are not typically considered “real” or universal quantum computers:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Difference Between IVG and IVF</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/diff-IGV-IVF/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Difference Between IVG and IVF"/><published>2024-12-02T19:47:45+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-02T19:47:45+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/diff-IGV-IVF</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/diff-IGV-IVF/"><![CDATA[<p>The main difference between <strong>IVG (In Vitro Gametogenesis)</strong> and <strong>IVF (In Vitro Fertilization)</strong> lies in their processes and applications in reproductive technology:</p> <h3 id="in-vitro-fertilization-ivf"><strong>In Vitro Fertilization (IVF):</strong></h3> <ul> <li><strong>What it is:</strong> A well-established fertility treatment where an egg is fertilized by sperm in a lab.</li> <li><strong>Key Steps:</strong> <ol> <li><strong>Ovarian stimulation:</strong> Medications stimulate a woman’s ovaries to produce multiple eggs.</li> <li><strong>Egg retrieval:</strong> Eggs are collected from the ovaries.</li> <li><strong>Fertilization:</strong> Eggs are combined with sperm in a laboratory to create embryos.</li> <li><strong>Embryo transfer:</strong> A selected embryo is implanted into the uterus.</li> </ol> </li> <li><strong>Applications:</strong> Helps individuals or couples with infertility, same-sex couples, and single parents conceive a child.</li> <li><strong>Established Technology:</strong> IVF has been used successfully for decades.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="in-vitro-gametogenesis-ivg"><strong>In Vitro Gametogenesis (IVG):</strong></h3> <ul> <li><strong>What it is:</strong> An emerging experimental technique where eggs and sperm are created from stem cells in a lab.</li> <li><strong>Key Steps:</strong> <ol> <li><strong>Stem cell derivation:</strong> Adult cells (like skin or blood cells) are reprogrammed into induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSCs).</li> <li><strong>Germ cell development:</strong> iPSCs are coaxed to develop into gametes (eggs or sperm) through lab protocols.</li> <li><strong>Fertilization:</strong> The lab-created eggs and sperm can be combined to create embryos, similar to IVF.</li> </ol> </li> <li><strong>Applications:</strong> Could one day provide fertility options for individuals who cannot produce viable gametes, such as: <ul> <li>Post-menopausal women.</li> <li>Men and women with genetic conditions affecting fertility.</li> <li>Same-sex couples wanting a biological child.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Experimental Stage:</strong> IVG is still in research and not yet available for clinical use.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="key-differences"><strong>Key Differences:</strong></h3> <table> <thead> <tr> <th>Feature</th> <th>IVF</th> <th>IVG</th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td><strong>Technology</strong></td> <td>Established and widely used.</td> <td>Experimental and in development.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Process</strong></td> <td>Uses existing eggs and sperm.</td> <td>Creates eggs and sperm in a lab.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Applications</strong></td> <td>Infertility treatment.</td> <td>Potential for broader fertility solutions.</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>Availability</strong></td> <td>Clinically available.</td> <td>Not yet available for humans.</td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <p>IVG holds transformative potential, but ethical, technical, and safety concerns must be addressed before it can become a practical option.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Gametogenesis</strong> is the biological process by which <strong>gametes</strong> (sex cells, such as sperm and eggs) are formed in sexually reproducing organisms. It occurs in the gonads (testes in males and ovaries in females) and involves a series of cellular divisions and maturation steps to produce gametes capable of participating in fertilization.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="types-of-gametogenesis"><strong>Types of Gametogenesis:</strong></h3> <ol> <li><strong>Spermatogenesis</strong> (Formation of sperm cells): <ul> <li><strong>Location:</strong> Testes (in the seminiferous tubules).</li> <li><strong>Process:</strong> <ul> <li>Begins with <strong>spermatogonia</strong> (diploid stem cells) undergoing mitosis.</li> <li>Some spermatogonia differentiate into <strong>primary spermatocytes</strong>, which enter meiosis.</li> <li>Meiosis I produces <strong>secondary spermatocytes</strong> (haploid).</li> <li>Meiosis II produces <strong>spermatids</strong>, which further mature into <strong>spermatozoa</strong> (functional sperm cells).</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Timeframe:</strong> Continuous process after puberty in males.</li> <li><strong>Result:</strong> Millions of sperm are produced daily.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Oogenesis</strong> (Formation of egg cells or ova): <ul> <li><strong>Location:</strong> Ovaries.</li> <li><strong>Process:</strong> <ul> <li>Begins before birth with <strong>oogonia</strong> (diploid stem cells) dividing by mitosis to form <strong>primary oocytes</strong>.</li> <li>Primary oocytes begin meiosis but are arrested at prophase I until puberty.</li> <li>During each menstrual cycle, a primary oocyte completes meiosis I, forming a <strong>secondary oocyte</strong> and a polar body.</li> <li>Meiosis II is completed only if the secondary oocyte is fertilized.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Timeframe:</strong> Cyclical and limited; females are born with a finite number of oocytes.</li> <li><strong>Result:</strong> Typically, one mature ovum is released per menstrual cycle.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <hr/> <h3 id="key-features-of-gametogenesis"><strong>Key Features of Gametogenesis:</strong></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Meiosis:</strong> A specialized type of cell division that reduces the chromosome number by half (from diploid to haploid) to ensure the gametes contain only one set of chromosomes.</li> <li><strong>Haploid Cells:</strong> Gametes are haploid (23 chromosomes in humans), ensuring that when an egg and sperm combine during fertilization, the resulting zygote is diploid (46 chromosomes in humans).</li> <li><strong>Sex Differences:</strong> Spermatogenesis is a continuous and prolific process, while oogenesis is cyclic and produces fewer gametes.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="importance-of-gametogenesis"><strong>Importance of Gametogenesis:</strong></h3> <ul> <li>Essential for <strong>sexual reproduction</strong>, as it ensures genetic diversity through meiotic recombination and independent assortment.</li> <li>Facilitates the combination of genetic material from two parents, forming offspring with unique genetic traits.</li> </ul> <hr/> <iframe width="720" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/88DPXE1thw4?si=LNrIWyAgYQnFVOF1" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="biology"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The main difference between IVG (In Vitro Gametogenesis) and IVF (In Vitro Fertilization) lies in their processes and applications in reproductive technology:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ponderomotive Force</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Ponderomotive-force/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ponderomotive Force"/><published>2024-11-16T14:25:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-16T14:25:00+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Ponderomotive-force</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Ponderomotive-force/"><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>ponderomotive force</strong> is a non-linear, oscillation-averaged force experienced by charged particles in a rapidly oscillating electromagnetic field, such as that in a laser beam. Unlike forces directly associated with electromagnetic fields (e.g., Lorentz force), the ponderomotive force arises due to spatial variations in the intensity of the oscillating field.</p> <h3 id="key-features-of-ponderomotive-force">Key Features of Ponderomotive Force:</h3> <ol> <li><strong>Nature</strong>: <ul> <li>It is time-averaged, meaning it acts over the period of oscillation of the electromagnetic field.</li> <li>It is a repulsive force, pushing particles away from regions of higher field intensity.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Expression</strong>: <ul> <li>For a charged particle of mass \(m\) and charge \(q\), the ponderomotive force \(F_p\) is given by:</li> <li> \[F_p = -\frac{q^2}{4m\omega^2} \nabla |E|^2\] </li> </ul> <p>where:</p> <ul> <li>\(E\) is the electric field strength,</li> <li>\(\omega\) is the angular frequency of the oscillating field,</li> <li>\(\nabla E^2\) represents the gradient of the field intensity.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Mechanism</strong>: <ul> <li>The oscillatory motion caused by the electric field is slightly stronger in regions of higher intensity. This imbalance results in a net drift of the particle away from those regions.</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Applications</strong>: <ul> <li><strong>Laser-plasma interactions</strong>: Plays a role in laser-driven acceleration of particles.</li> <li><strong>Trapping and guiding</strong>: Used in optical traps and the manipulation of particles.</li> <li><strong>Astrophysics</strong>: Relevant in analyzing particle behavior in varying electromagnetic fields in space.</li> </ul> </li> </ol> <h3 id="intuition">Intuition:</h3> <p>The ponderomotive force can be thought of as a “pressure” exerted by an oscillating electromagnetic field on charged particles, driving them toward regions of lower field intensity.</p> <p>The term <strong>“ponderomotive”</strong> comes from the Latin root <em>pondero</em>, meaning “to weigh” or “to consider,” reflecting the concept of a force that results from the cumulative effect of oscillating fields on charged particles. Here’s how it relates to the <strong>ponderomotive force</strong>:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Averaging Effect</strong>:<br/> The ponderomotive force does not act instantaneously with the oscillating electric field but is the result of the <em>time-averaged effect</em> of these oscillations. The oscillations “ponder” (consider, weigh) over time to produce a net force.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Directional Behavior</strong>:<br/> The force moves particles away from regions of high electromagnetic field intensity, as if “considering” or “weighing” the field’s spatial variations.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Energy Interpretation</strong>:<br/> The word ponderomotive suggests a relationship with the energy gradient. The force arises from the need to balance the energy density across regions of the electromagnetic field, similar to how pressure gradients drive fluid motion.</p> </li> </ol> <h3 id="in-context">In Context:</h3> <p>The <strong>ponderomotive force</strong> is not about direct action but about how particles “sense” the overall structure of the field through the oscillatory motion. The terminology emphasizes the gradual, considered, and collective influence of the field on particle behavior, distinguishing it from immediate forces like the Lorentz force.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="reference">Reference</h3> <ul> <li>Yan, Wenchao, et al. “High-order multiphoton Thomson scattering.” Nature Photonics 11.8 (2017): 514-520.</li> </ul> <hr/> <h3 id="helpful-video">Helpful Video</h3> <iframe width="720" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/97O2sxcXu64?si=2iRUhXg-U2Yv8pEY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="physics"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ponderomotive force is a non-linear, oscillation-averaged force experienced by charged particles in a rapidly oscillating electromagnetic field, such as that in a laser beam. Unlike forces directly associated with electromagnetic fields (e.g., Lorentz force), the ponderomotive force arises due to spatial variations in the intensity of the oscillating field.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Oncolytic Viruses Work</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Oncolytic_Virus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Oncolytic Viruses Work"/><published>2024-11-11T00:11:14+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T00:11:14+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Oncolytic_Virus</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Oncolytic_Virus/"><![CDATA[<iframe width="720" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/M7YcKtncTwc?si=0MwqX_BqOz6LQRsg" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="BioEnginerring"/><category term="Virus"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Core Courses of BioEngineer</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Learning-Bioengineering/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Core Courses of BioEngineer"/><published>2024-11-08T22:07:38+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-08T22:07:38+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Learning-Bioengineering</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Learning-Bioengineering/"><![CDATA[<p>To prepare for advanced work in biological engineering and bridge your physics and computational background with biological sciences, focusing on a few core areas can be incredibly helpful. Here’s a list of commonly used textbooks that I could self-study in foundational courses:</p> <h3 id="1-cell-and-molecular-biology">1. <strong>Cell and Molecular Biology</strong></h3> <ul> <li> <p><strong>“Molecular Biology of the Cell”</strong> by Bruce Alberts et al.<br/> This is a comprehensive text covering the principles of cell structure, function, and molecular biology. It’s widely used for understanding cellular mechanisms and molecular processes.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>“Essential Cell Biology”</strong> by Bruce Alberts et al.<br/> A more accessible version of the previous book, this text simplifies many complex ideas, providing a clearer overview if you’re just starting with cell biology concepts.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>“Molecular Cell Biology”</strong> by Harvey Lodish et al.<br/> This book emphasizes molecular processes and gene regulation with an integrated approach, covering the bridge between cell biology and genetics.</p> </li> </ul> <h3 id="2-genetics-and-genomics">2. <strong>Genetics and Genomics</strong></h3> <ul> <li> <p><strong>“Introduction to Genetic Analysis”</strong> by Anthony J.F. Griffiths et al.<br/> This text covers core genetics principles, from Mendelian genetics to modern molecular genetics. It also touches on genomics, which is essential for understanding CRISPR and other gene-editing techniques.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>“Genomes”</strong> by T.A. Brown<br/> A practical book that delves into genome structure, function, and bioinformatics, it can be a good reference for understanding how genetics connects to larger biological systems.</p> </li> </ul> <h3 id="3-biochemistry">3. <strong>Biochemistry</strong></h3> <ul> <li> <p><strong>“Lehninger Principles of Biochemistry”</strong> by David L. Nelson and Michael M. Cox<br/> A foundational book for biochemistry, it covers metabolism, protein structure, and enzyme kinetics, all of which are essential for biological engineering and cellular reprogramming studies.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>“Biochemistry”</strong> by Jeremy M. Berg, John L. Tymoczko, and Lubert Stryer<br/> Known for clear explanations, this book delves into the chemistry of life, with practical applications relevant to biomedical research and molecular biology.</p> </li> </ul> <h3 id="4-bioengineering-and-synthetic-biology">4. <strong>Bioengineering and Synthetic Biology</strong></h3> <ul> <li> <p><strong>“Biodesign: The Process of Innovating Medical Technologies”</strong> by Paul G. Yock et al.<br/> This book provides a framework for applying engineering principles to biological and medical innovations, focusing on problem-solving and the design process.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>“Molecular Biotechnology: Principles and Applications of Recombinant DNA”</strong> by Bernard Glick, Jack Pasternak, and Cheryl Patten<br/> Covering essential techniques in biotechnology, this text provides insights into gene editing, recombinant DNA, and protein expression.</p> </li> </ul> <h3 id="5-systems-and-computational-biology">5. <strong>Systems and Computational Biology</strong></h3> <ul> <li> <p><strong>“Systems Biology: A Textbook”</strong> by Edda Klipp et al.<br/> A useful text for understanding the modeling and simulation of complex biological systems, integrating cellular and molecular biology with computational approaches.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>“Biological Physics: Energy, Information, Life”</strong> by Philip Nelson<br/> This book explores the physical principles underlying biological systems, giving you insight into the physics-biology interface and the applications of statistical mechanics to molecular biology.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>“Computational Biology: A Practical Introduction to BioData Processing and Analysis”</strong> by Röbbe Wünschiers<br/> A hands-on book that provides practical skills in bioinformatics and computational analysis, which will be crucial in fields like genomics and proteomics.</p> </li> </ul> <h3 id="6-advanced-topics-in-stem-cells-and-regenerative-medicine">6. <strong>Advanced Topics in Stem Cells and Regenerative Medicine</strong></h3> <ul> <li> <p><strong>“Stem Cells: An Insider’s Guide”</strong> by Paul Knoepfler<br/> An accessible book for understanding the potential and applications of stem cells, including ethical considerations.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>“Principles of Regenerative Medicine”</strong> by Anthony Atala et al.<br/> This book provides a comprehensive overview of regenerative medicine applications, integrating stem cell research with practical therapies.</p> </li> </ul> <p>Each of these books represents a core area of study relevant to your interests in biological engineering. Supplementing this study with recent journal articles in bioengineering, computational biology, and biophysics will keep you updated on cutting-edge techniques and discoveries.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="code"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I will teach myself on biological engineering]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bioengineering PhD Program Deadline</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Bioengineering-deadline/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bioengineering PhD Program Deadline"/><published>2024-11-02T23:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-02T23:04:00+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Bioengineering-deadline</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/Bioengineering-deadline/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="berkeley">Berkeley</h2> <h3 id="deadline-december-1">Deadline: December 1</h3> <ul> <li>Fee: 155$</li> <li>Apply at https://gradapp.berkeley.edu/apply/ <ul> <li> <p>We invite applications from students with a strong interest in the life sciences and demonstrated strength in mathematics and physical sciences. Consideration is also given to applicants with strong, relevant life science backgrounds who have demonstrated quantitative skills. Our program attracts motivated, independent students with a diversity of experience who are eager to contribute to the growing field of bioengineering.</p> </li> <li> <p>We are particularly interested in providing educational opportunities for students from diverse populations, including student parents, veterans, disabled persons, and scholars historically underrepresented in the biological and engineering disciplines.</p> </li> <li> <p>Anyone with a Bachelor of Arts or Bachelor of Science degree in engineering, biology, or other sciences, is eligible for admission. Appropriate academic preparation includes a two-year college mathematics sequence, including calculus and differential equations, and a one-year sequence in physics and chemistry, plus extensive upper-division work in either engineering or biology. A course in linear algebra is highly desirable. Outstanding students lacking some of these requirements may be admitted on the condition that they complete the basic entrance requirements immediately after admission.</p> </li> <li> <p>In addition to the above undergraduate work, a successful applicant generally has a minimum grade point average of 3.5 or higher (on a 4.0 scale), and three strong letters of recommendation from faculty with whom they have worked closely. Most of our successful applicants also have some prior research experience.</p> </li> </ul> </li> </ul> <h3 id="labs">Labs</h3> <ol> <li><strong>Jennifer Doudna</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Genome editing, CRISPR-Cas9, synthetic biology, and gene regulation.</li> <li><em>Landmark Work:</em> Co-inventor of CRISPR-Cas9 gene-editing technology.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://doudnalab.org/">Doudna Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>David Schaffer</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Stem cell engineering, gene therapy, regenerative medicine, and synthetic biology.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Development of new gene delivery systems and understanding stem cell behaviors for regenerative applications.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://bioeng.berkeley.edu/faculty-research/schaffer">Schaffer Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Amy Herr</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Bioengineering of molecular diagnostic tools, microfluidic technologies, and quantitative biology.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Development of microfluidic technologies for studying proteins and understanding cell biology at the molecular level.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://herrlab.berkeley.edu/">Herr Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Irina Conboy</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Aging, regenerative medicine, tissue engineering, and molecular mechanisms of cellular regeneration.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Research on aging and rejuvenation of tissues, especially in the context of muscle and other organ systems.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://bioeng.berkeley.edu/faculty-research/conboy">Conboy Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Dan Fletcher</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Cell mechanics, bioengineering, biophysics, and imaging technologies.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Application of biophysical techniques to understand cellular structure, function, and communication.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://fletcherlab.berkeley.edu/">Fletcher Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Sanjay Kumar</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Cellular biomechanics, stem cell biology, biomaterials, and synthetic biology.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Exploration of how cells respond to physical stimuli, with implications for regenerative medicine.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://kumarlab.berkeley.edu/">Kumar Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Kiana Aran</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Development of biosensing devices, synthetic biology, and applications of CRISPR-based diagnostics.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Innovation of electronic biosensors, particularly for detecting molecular and cellular processes.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://bioeng.berkeley.edu/faculty-research/aran">Aran Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Luke Lee</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Integrative biosystems, bioengineering, microfluidics, and synthetic biology.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Creation of novel bio-integrative systems for studying cellular interactions and biomolecular processes.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://vcresearch.berkeley.edu/faculty/luke-p-lee">Lee Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Niren Murthy</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Drug delivery, biomaterials, gene therapy, and tissue engineering.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Development of targeted drug delivery and gene delivery platforms with applications in regenerative medicine.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://bioeng.berkeley.edu/faculty-research/murthy">Murthy Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Evan Variano</strong> <ul> <li><em>Research Focus:</em> Environmental and biological fluid mechanics, biophysics, and applications in microbial and cellular behavior.</li> <li><em>Notable Work:</em> Study of fluid mechanics in biological systems, with relevance to synthetic biology and cellular environments.</li> <li><em>Lab Website:</em> <a href="https://bioeng.berkeley.edu/faculty-research/variano">Variano Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> </ol> <h2 id="stanford">Stanford</h2> <ul> <li>Good to go</li> </ul> <h2 id="harvard">Harvard</h2> <h3 id="deadline-december-15">Deadline: December 15</h3> <ul> <li>Apply at https://gsas.harvard.edu/apply</li> <li>Fee: 105$</li> <li>Info: https://seas.harvard.edu/bioengineering/graduate-program/how-apply</li> </ul> <h2 id="mit">MIT</h2> <h3 id="deadline--december-15">Deadline: December 15</h3> <ul> <li>Apply at https://apply.mit.edu/apply/</li> <li>Fee: 90$</li> </ul> <h3 id="biological-engineering-core">Biological Engineering Core:</h3> <ul> <li>20.420J Principles of Molecular Bioengineering</li> <li>20.440 Analysis of Biological Networks</li> </ul> <h4 id="academic-preparation">Academic preparation</h4> <ul> <li>Success in the challenging coursework and research components of the MIT BE PhD program requires a strong academic background in both biology and quantitative engineering or science. While many successful applicants hold undergraduate engineering degrees and have completed substantial coursework in biology, there are different ways to demonstrate the academic preparation needed. Applicants whose principal degree is quantitative, computational, engineering, or in the physical sciences can bolster their training in biology by taking core biology courses like biochemistry, genetics, and cell biology. Applicants whose principal degree is in a life science field can acquire quantitative training in courses beyond calculus, biostatistics, and programming/informatics such as differential equations, linear algebra, and advanced courses in probability, statistics, analysis, and computer science.</li> </ul> <h2 id="ucsd">UCSD</h2> <h3 id="deadline--december-4">Deadline: December 4</h3> <ul> <li>Apply at https://connect.grad.ucsd.edu/apply <h3 id="labs-1">Labs</h3> <p>Top professors at UC San Diego (UCSD) who align with your interests in bioengineering, regenerative medicine, stem cell research, and gene editing, here are five faculty members who may be a great fit:</p> </li> </ul> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Dr. Kun Zhang</strong><br/> <strong>Position:</strong> Professor and Chair, Department of Bioengineering<br/> <strong>Research Focus:</strong> Dr. Zhang’s research is in genome sequencing, epigenomics, and single-cell genomics, with applications in understanding complex diseases, stem cell biology, and developmental processes. His lab focuses on how genetic and epigenetic information guides stem cell differentiation, which aligns well with your interest in understanding the molecular mechanisms behind cellular behavior and regenerative medicine.<br/> <strong>Lab Page:</strong> <a href="https://bioengineering.ucsd.edu/people/faculty/faculty-directory/faculty-profile-kun-zhang.html">Kun Zhang Lab</a></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Dr. Shyni Varghese</strong><br/> <strong>Position:</strong> Professor, Department of Bioengineering and Material Science and Engineering<br/> <strong>Research Focus:</strong> Dr. Varghese works at the intersection of bioengineering and regenerative medicine, particularly in biomaterials and stem cell-based therapies. Her lab explores how physical cues in the cellular environment influence stem cell behavior, aiming to develop therapies for tissue regeneration, which may interest you due to the connection with physical principles in cellular behavior.<br/> <strong>Lab Page:</strong> <a href="https://bioengineering.ucsd.edu/people/faculty/faculty-directory/faculty-profile-shyni-varghese.html">Varghese Lab</a></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Dr. Todd Coleman</strong><br/> <strong>Position:</strong> Professor, Department of Bioengineering<br/> <strong>Research Focus:</strong> Dr. Coleman’s work involves integrating neural engineering, bioinformatics, and computational neuroscience to understand biological systems. He uses machine learning and data-driven approaches to model complex biological processes, which aligns with your background in computational and machine learning applications for biological engineering.<br/> <strong>Lab Page:</strong> <a href="https://bioengineering.ucsd.edu/people/faculty/faculty-directory/faculty-profile-todd-coleman.html">Coleman Lab</a></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Dr. Prashant Mali</strong><br/> <strong>Position:</strong> Associate Professor, Department of Bioengineering<br/> <strong>Research Focus:</strong> Dr. Mali is known for his work in gene editing and synthetic biology. His lab applies CRISPR-based technologies to understand cellular behavior and develop potential therapeutic applications, particularly in regenerative medicine and immunotherapy. This focus on gene editing technologies aligns directly with your interest in exploring fundamental biological processes and regenerative medicine.<br/> <strong>Lab Page:</strong> <a href="https://mali.ucsd.edu/">Mali Lab</a></p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Dr. Gene Yeo</strong><br/> <strong>Position:</strong> Professor, Department of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, and Bioengineering<br/> <strong>Research Focus:</strong> Dr. Yeo’s lab specializes in RNA biology and gene regulation, using computational biology and machine learning to study RNA processing in stem cells and disease contexts. His research is relevant to understanding molecular mechanisms and has applications in gene therapies and regenerative medicine, intersecting well with your interest in computational and biological engineering.<br/> <strong>Lab Page:</strong> <a href="https://yeolab.github.io/">Yeo Lab</a></p> </li> </ol> <h2 id="uw">UW</h2> <h3 id="deadline-dec-2">Deadline: Dec 2</h3> <ul> <li>Apply at https://apply.grad.uw.edu/portal/gr_app</li> <li>Fee: 85$</li> </ul> <h4 id="addtional-requirement">Addtional Requirement</h4> <ul> <li>1-2 laboratory rotations during the first year. If needed, a third rotation must be approved by petition to the Graduate Student Affairs Committee.</li> <li>1-quarter teaching experience – either a TAship or grader with student contract position. This requirement can be completed at any point during the PhD degree but is encouraged to be undertaken after the second year.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="images"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Berkeley Deadline: December 1 Fee: 155$ Apply at https://gradapp.berkeley.edu/apply/ We invite applications from students with a strong interest in the life sciences and demonstrated strength in mathematics and physical sciences. Consideration is also given to applicants with strong, relevant life science backgrounds who have demonstrated quantitative skills. Our program attracts motivated, independent students with a diversity of experience who are eager to contribute to the growing field of bioengineering.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">List of Researchers for Biological Engieering</title><link href="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/professor-list/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="List of Researchers for Biological Engieering"/><published>2024-11-02T05:19:16+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-02T05:19:16+00:00</updated><id>https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/professor-list</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chunde.github.io/blog/2024/professor-list/"><![CDATA[<p>Here is a list of professors in biological engineering, synthetic biology, or related fields, with their landmark publications where they are listed as first or corresponding authors. These researchers have contributed significantly to fields like CRISPR gene editing, synthetic biology, protein design, and systems biology.</p> <hr/> <ol> <li><strong>Feng Zhang</strong> - MIT, Massachusetts <ul> <li><strong>Landmark Paper</strong>: <em>“Genome editing with CRISPR-Cas systems”</em> (Science, 2013)</li> <li><a href="https://www.broadinstitute.org/bios/feng-zhang">Link to Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Jennifer Doudna</strong> - University of California, Berkeley, California <ul> <li><strong>Landmark Paper</strong>: <em>“A programmable dual-RNA-guided DNA endonuclease in adaptive bacterial immunity”</em> (Science, 2012)</li> <li><a href="https://doudnalab.org/">Link to Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>David Baker</strong> - University of Washington, Washington <ul> <li><strong>Landmark Paper</strong>: <em>“Accurate design of co-assembling multi-component protein nanomaterials”</em> (Nature, 2016)</li> <li><a href="https://www.bakerlab.org/">Link to Lab</a></li> </ul> </li> </ol> <hr/> <ul> <li>These professors span a wide range of relevant areas from molecular engineering and synthetic biology to computational biology and gene regulation, each offering a unique perspective that would be valuable in exploring biological engineering’s many interdisciplinary facets.</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="2024"/><category term="Application"/><category term="Bioogy"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here is a list of professors in biological engineering, synthetic biology, or related fields, with their landmark publications where they are listed as first or corresponding authors. These researchers have contributed significantly to fields like CRISPR gene editing, synthetic biology, protein design, and systems biology.]]></summary></entry></feed>